（ 新年快乐 女士 ）
（ Happy New Year's, ladies. ）
盖比 今晚是跨年夜 别读书了
Gabby, it's New Year's Eve. Enough reading.
哦 妈妈 马上就完了
Oh, Mom, I'm almost done.
派对呢？我准备了你最好的衣服 来吧
The teen party? I've laid out your best clothes. Come get ready.
-谢谢 -来吧
-Thank you. -Come on.
一直攻左路 特洛伊
Keep working left, Troy.
得到冠军赛的后卫位置 我们希望你能打垮他们！
Got a guard in the championship game we're expectin'. You'll torch 'em!
能把书还我吗？
Can I have my book back?
-向左？-对
-Am I going left? -Yeah.
-他向中路 你投篮 -像这样？
-He looks middle, you take it downtown. -OK,like this?
喔！对了 用在比赛中吧
Whoo! That's it, man. Sweet. Let's see that in the game.
-男孩们？-别担心我
-Boys? -Don't worry about me.
我们那么远飞到这里就为了继续打篮球？
Did we really fly all this way to play more basketball?
对
Yeah.
这是假期的最后一天
It's the last night of vacation.
派对 记得吗？
The party, remember?
对 派对 派对 跨年夜
Right, the party. The party. New Year's Eve.
特洛伊 他们在楼下俱乐部有青少年派对
Troy, they have a kid's party downstairs in the Freestyle club.
-青少年派对 -年轻人的 去吧 洗个澡
- Kid's party? - Young adults. Now go, shower up.
好 就再来一个
Come on. One more.
-最后一个 -很快
-Last one. -Real quick.
好 这是我们结束的方法
There we go. That's the way to end it.
你好女士
Howdy, ma'am.
好！滑雪的人来个吧？
All right! How about that for a couple of snowboarders?
-好！-嗨！
-Yeah! -Hey!
谁是下一个呢？
Who's gonna rock the house next?
嗯？
Huh?
哈哈！嗬！
Ha-ha! Ho-ho!
我不会唱 不 你来吧
I can't sing. No, you go.
你！来 来吧
And you! Yeah, come on.
看 我不会唱歌 别 伙计...
Look, I don't sing. I can't sing. No, guys...
上来 上来吧！
Get up there! Get up
嘿 知道吗？有朝一日你们会感谢我的
Hey, you know what? Someday you guys might thank me for this.
也许不
Or not.
活在自我的世界里
Living in my own world
一点都不明白
Didn't understand
一切皆有可能
That anything can happen
只要你勇于冒险
When you take a chance
我从不相信
I never believed in
不是亲眼所见之事
What I couldn't see
我从不曾敞开心扉
I never opened my heart
噢~
Oh~
迎接任何可能性
To all the possibilities
哦~
Ooh~
-我知道 事情有了变化
-I know -That something has changed
从来没有过这样的感觉
Never felt this way
就在今晚
And right here tonight
这可能是一个全新的起点
This could be the start Of something new
和你在一起
To be here with you
噢~
Oh~
此刻注视你的双眸
And now looking in your eyes
我感觉在我心里 -感觉在我心中
I feel in my heart -Feel in my heart
感觉如此的美妙
It feels so right
全新的旅程已然开始
The start of something new
噢~耶~
Oh~Yeah~
谁都不曾预料到
Now who'd of ever thought that
我们相遇在今晚
We'd both be here tonight
哦~耶~
Ooh~Yeah~
世界也变得更加明亮起来
And the world looks so much brighter
-明亮 明亮起来 -哦
-Brighter brighter -Oh.
有你在我身旁 -在我身旁
With you by my side -By my side.
我知道事情有了变化
I know that something has changed
从来有过如此感受
Never felt this way
-我十分肯定 -十分肯定
-I know it for real -Real
这是一场全新的旅程
This could be the start of something new
感觉如此的美妙
It feels so right
和你在一起
To be here with you
噢~
Oh~
此刻注视你的双眸
And now looking in your eyes
全新的旅程已然开始
The start of something new
我从未知晓它会发生
I never knew that it could happen
降临在我的身上
Till it happened to me
我感觉在我心里
I feel in my heart
噢~耶~
Oh~Yeah~
过去我从未知晓
I didn't know it before
但现在却显而易见
But now it's easy to see
噢~
Oh~
这是一场全新的旅程
It's the start of something new
感觉如此的美妙
It feels so right
和你在一起
To be here with you
噢~
Oh~
此刻注视你的双眸
And now looking in your eyes
我感觉在我心里
I feel in my heart
全新的旅程已然开始
That it's the start of something new
感觉如此的美妙
It feels so right
和你在一起 -哦~
to be here with you -Oh~
此刻注视你的双眸
And now looking in your eyes
我感觉在我心里 -感觉在我心中
I feel in my heart -Feel in my heart
全新的旅程已然开始
The start of something new
-特洛伊 -盖比瑞拉
-Troy. -Gabriella.
说真的 你的嗓音真好
But seriously, you have an amazing voice.
你是个歌手 对吧？
You're a singer, right?
只是在教堂的唱诗班唱过
Just church choir is all.
我试过独唱 但差点昏倒
I tried to solo and nearly fainted.
真的？为什么？
Really? Why is that?
我看到人们在盯着我
I looked at the people staring at me.
然后我就只敢盯着天花板
Next thing I knew, I was staring at the ceiling.
独唱生涯就结束了
End of solo career.
看你唱歌的样子 很难相信
The way you sing, that's hard to believe.
这是我第一次当众唱歌 很过瘾
That was the first time I did that. It was so cool.
我知道！棒极了！
I know! Completely!
听起来你唱歌经验很丰富
You sound like you've sung a lot, too.
哦 对 我家的淋浴喷头有深刻印像
Yeah, sure. My showerhead is very impressed with me.
九 八 七
Nine, Eight, Seven...
六 五 四
Six, Five, Four...
三 二 一
Three, Two, One!
我想我最好找到我妈妈
I guess I better go find my mom
祝她新年快乐
and wish her a happy new year.
哦 我也是
Yeah, me too.
我指的不是你妈妈 是我妈妈和爸爸
I mean, not your mom. My mom... and dad.
呃 我给你电话 我明天打给你
Uh... I'll call you. I'll call you tomorrow.
-对！-存你的号码
-Yeah! -Here, put your number in.
这
Here.
-你也是 -噢 好
-You too. -Oh, OK.
给你
There you go.
你知道吗 和你唱歌
Just so you know, singing with you
是我这次假期最高兴的事
was the most fun I've had on this vacation.
那么 你住在哪里？
So, um... where do you live?
盖比瑞拉
Gabriella.
野猫们一起唱 你们真的一级棒
Wildcats sing along They really got it going on
屋子里的野猫们 每个人都齐声唱
Wildcats in the house Everybody sing out
各地的野猫们 居高双手向上跳
Wildcats. Everywhere wave your hands up in the air
这就是我们擅长之事
That's the way we do it let's get to it
来像世人一展长才吧
Time to show the world
野猫们一起唱 你们真的一级棒
Wildcats. Sing along They really got it goin' on
屋子里的野猫们 每个人都齐声唱
Wildcats in the house everybody sing out...
-特洛伊 你好吗？ -嘿 查德 怎么样？
-Troy! How ya doing, man? -Hey, Chad, what's up?
-嗨 伙计 新年快乐  -嗨！
-Hey, guys, happy new year. -Yeah!
-野猫队的新年快乐！ -你真行！
-It's a happy Wildcat new year! -You're the man!
还有两周 我们就要冲击冠军了
In two weeks we're going to the championships
有你带领我们一直冲顶
with you leading us to infinity and beyond.
-哪只队？ -野猫队！
-What team? -Wildcats!
噢！哦-哦！
Ooh! Whoo-hoo!
噢!
Ooh !
冰公主从北极回来了
The ice princess returned from the North Pole.
-什么方法？ -买镜子
-How's that? -Shopping for mirrors.
喔！
Ooh!
呃 瞧动物园的猛兽 宣布新年 多有个性
Ugh, behold the zoo animals heralding the new year. How tribal.
她用通常的方法过了节
She spent the holidays the way she always does.
妈妈 我的胃...
Mom, my stomach...
是第一天在新学校的紧张
Is nervous on first day at a new school.
你会好很好的 你总是这样
Is nervous on first day at a new school. You'll do great. You always do.
我要我的公司答应
I made my company promise
在你毕业前我不会再调动了
that I can't be transferred again until you graduate.
我看过你优异的成绩单
I reviewed your impressive transcripts.
相信在东高你同样会出类拔萃的
Your light will shine brightly at East High.
我不想再成为学校里古怪的天才女孩
I don't want to be the school's freaky genius girl again.
你就是盖比瑞拉
Just be Gabriella.
这边请
This way.
特洛伊 特洛伊 嘿
Troy! Troy! Hey!
怎么样？你好吗？
How's it goin'? How are you?
达布丝老师？
Miss Darbus?
-你记得那一晚吗？ -不 完全忘了
-Do you remember the night before? - No, not at all.
我只记得 粉红果冻 我...
All I remember is like, pink jelly. I...
对不起
Excuse me.
哦！
Ooh!
嗨 特洛伊
Hi, Troy.
嗨
Hi.
相信大家假期都过得很愉快
I trust you all had splendid holidays.
你们需要去看走廊里新公布的课外活动表
Check the sign-up sheets in the lobby for new activities,
波顿同学
Mr. Bolton.
特别是我们的冬季音乐会
Especially our winter musicale.
我们会有独唱的试镜为了...
We will have singles auditions...
-你没事吧？ -嗯
-You OK? -Yeah.
还有俩人的领唱的试镜
...and pairs auditions for our two leads.
呲噗~
Pfft~
丹弗斯同学 这是教室
Mr. Danforth, this is a place of learning,
不是曲棍球场
not a hockey arena.
还有下周学术全能竞赛的报名 即将截止
There is also a final sign-up for next week's scholastic decathlon competition.
化学社社长泰勒·麦肯锡
Chem Club president Taylor McHessey
会回答你们的问题
can answer all of your questions about that.
啊 手机又来
Ah, the cell phone menace
危害我们的学习环境了
has returned to our crucible of learning.
-是你的手机吗？ -夏培和瑞安 手机
-Is it your phone? -Sharpay and Ryan, cell phones.
-我会罚你留堂 -啊！
-I will see you in detention. -Ahh!
课堂上绝不准使用手机
We have zero tolerance for cell phones in class,
我们正好可以借此认识彼此 手机
so we will get to know each other in detention. Cell phone.
欢迎来到东部高中 蒙特兹同学
And welcome to East High, Miss Montez.
波顿同学 我看到你的手机也在作怪
Mr. Bolton, I see your phone is involved.
-所以你也要留堂
So we will see you in detention as well.
不可能 达布丝老师
That's not a possibility, Miss Darbus.
您看 我们必须练习篮球 而特洛伊..
Your Honor, see, 'cause we have basketball practice, and Troy...
呃 你也一样留校15分钟
Ah, that will be 15 minutes for you too
丹弗斯同学 计时吧
Mr. Danforth. Count 'em.
对查德来说太难了
Could be tough for Chad.
他数不了那么多
He can't count that high.
泰勒·麦肯锡 留堂15分钟
Taylor McHessey, 15 minutes.
还有人继续要留堂吗？
Shall the carnage continue?
假期结束了 同学们
Holidays are over, people.
好了！谁还有什么建议或问题？
Way over! Now, any more comments, questions?
杰森
-Jason.
假期过得好吗 达布丝老师？
How were your holidays, Miss Darbus?
怎么？
What?
对不起 留堂时见
-Sorry, man. See you in detention.
待会见 没关系的
See you later. It's all good.
喔 她疯了
Uhh, she's crazy.
嗨！
Hey!
-我不敢... -相信
- I don't... -Believe it.
-嗯 我... -但 现在？
- Well, me... - Either. But how?
我妈妈被公司调到
My mom's company transferred her here
阿尔伯克郡来了
to Albuquerque.
真不敢相信你住在这里
I can't believe you live here.
新年那天我一直在找你
I looked for you at the lodge on New Year's Day.
我们一大早就得离开
We had to leave first thing.
你干嘛要小声说话？
Why are you whispering?
什么？
What?
喔 呃 我的朋友们只知道我滑雪的事
Oh, uh... my friends know about the snowboarding.
我还没有讲唱歌的事情
I haven't quite told them about the singing thing.
-嗨 特洛伊 -嗨
-Hi, Troy. -Hey.
- 怕他们接受不了？ -不 也不是
-Too much for them to handle? - No, it was cool.
只是他们不会相信 嗯...我会当众唱歌
But, you know, my friends, it's, uh... It's not what I do.
就好像..是另一个完全不同的人
That was, like, a different person.
呃 总而言之 欢迎来到东部高中
So, uh... anyway, welcome to East High.
你已经见过达布丝老师了
Now that you've met Miss Darbus,
我猜你一定等不及要去报名了
I bet you just can't wait to sign up for that.
我暂时还不想报名参加活动
I won't be signing up for anything for a while.
我只想先多了解一下这所学校
I just wanna get to know the school.
不过要是你参加
But if you sign up,
我会考虑看你的表演的
I'd consider coming to the show.
哦 谢谢 那是完全不可能的
-Yeah, yeah. That's completely impossible.
什么不可能 特洛伊？
What's impossible, Troy?
我从没想到你的字典里也里有"不可能"
I wouldn't think "impossible" is even in your vocabulary.
哦 你还真热心 带新同学认识一下校园
Oh, so nice of you to show our new classmate around.
哦 你也要报名吗？
Oh, were you going to sign up too?
我弟弟和我一向主演所有音乐剧
My brother and I have starred in all the school's productions
我们十分欢迎新同学
and we really welcome newcomers.
剧里有许多的配角
There are a lot of supporting roles.
相信一定有适合你的角色
I'm sure we could find something for you.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
我只是在看所有的公告栏
I was just looking at all the bulletin boards.
学校的活动真不少
Lots going on at this school.
哇哦
Wow.
签名不错
Nice penmanship.
特洛伊 假期时我很想你
So, Troy. I missed you during vacation.
你过得如何？
What'd you do?
你知道 嗯...打打篮球
You know, um... played basketball,
滑雪 还有打篮球
snowboarding, more basketball.
-什么时候决赛？-还有两周
-When's the big game? - Two weeks.
你这么专注 就像我
You are so dedicated. Just like me.
希望你能来看我的音乐演出
I hope you come watch me in the musical.
答应我？
Promise?
-再见 -再见
-Toodles! -Toodles.
伙计 你知道学校音乐演出的事吗？
Dude, you know that school musical thing?
呃...
Uh...
你只要参加就有加分
You get extra credit just for auditioning?
进入大学...
for college...
想想小皇帝杰姆斯 大鲨鱼奥尼尔
Think LeBron James or Shaquille O'Neal
会试镜学校的音乐剧演出？
auditioned for their school musical?
-也许 -特洛伊
-Maybe. -Troy.
这音乐演出不是说唱 摇滚
The music in those shows isn't hip-hop, or rock,
-谁在乎？ -有加分总是好事...
- Who cares? - It's always good to get extra credit...
或其他的文化经典
or anything essential to culture.
只是音乐秀
It's, like, show music.
服装和化妆
It's all costumes and makeup...
哦 伙计 太可怕了
Oh, dude, it's frightening.
我知道 我只是觉得那样很好玩
I know. I thought it'd be a good laugh.
你知道的
You know.
夏培也蛮可爱的
Sharpay's kinda cute, too.
是啊 美洲狮也同样可爱
So is a mountain lion.
只是你碰不得
But you don't pet it.
好 野猫队！集合！
All right, Wildcats! Pair up!
来吧！开始！
Let's go! Come on!
教练说虚右实左
Coach said to fake right and break left
加强进攻 留意防守
Watch out for the pick and keep an eye on defense
需要跑动 带球去空档
Gotta run the give and go and take the ball to the hole
不要担心远投
And don't be afraid to shoot the outside "J"
集中精力比赛 集中精力比赛
Just keep your head in the game Just keep your head in the game
不要担心远投不要担心远投
And don't be afraid to shoot the outside "J"
集中精力比赛 你要集中精力比赛
Just keep your head in the game You gotta get your head in the game
我们需要集中 集中 集中 集中精力比赛
We gotta get our, get our, get our, get our head in the game
你们需要集中 集中精力比赛
You gotta get your, get your head in the game
我们需要集中 集中 集中 集中精力比赛
We gotta get our, get our, get our, get our head in the game
来 你要集中 集中精力比赛
Come on, get your, get your head in the game
我们集中 集中 集中 集中精力比赛
We gotta get our, get our, get our, get our head in the game
你需要集中 集中精力比赛
You gotta get your, get your head in the game
我们需要集中 集中 集中 集中精力比赛
We gotta get our, get our, get our, get our head in the game
哦
Whoo!
让我们保证篮板
Let's make sure that we get the rebound
因为我们得到 观众就狂热
'Cause when we get it then the crowd'll go wild
第二次机会 抓住它
A second chance, gotta grab it and go
也许这次我们会正确
Maybe this time we'll hit the right notes
等等 注意时间和位置 等等 集中精力比赛
Wait a minute, not the time and place wait a minute, get my head in the game
等等 集中精力比赛
Wait a minute get my head in the game
等等 我需要集中 集中精力比赛
Wait a minute, wait a minute I gotta get my, get my head in the game
你需要集中 集中 集中 集中精力比赛
You gotta get your, get your, get your, get your head in the game
我需要集中 集中精力比赛
I gotta get my, get my head in the game
你需要集中 集中 集中 集中精力比赛
You gotta get your, get your, get your, get your head in the game
来 集中 集中精力比赛
Come on, get my, get my head in the game
你需要集中 集中 集中 集中精力比赛
You gotta get your, get your, get your, get your head in the game
我需要集中 集中精力比赛
I gotta get my, get my head in the game
你需要集中 集中 集中 集中精力比赛
You gotta get your, get your, get your, get your head in the game, whoo
我为什么觉得不妥？
Why am I feeling so wrong?
我脑中想着比赛 心中想着歌
My head's in the game but my heart's in the song
她要我感觉那么好
She makes this feel so right
我应该唱歌吗？
Should I go for it?
最好忘了它！
I better shake this. Yikes!
我需要集中 集中精力比赛
I gotta get my, get my head in the game
你需要集中 集中 集中 集中精力比赛
You gotta get your, get your, get your, get your head in the game
我需要 集中精力比赛
I gotta get my, get my head in the game
你需要集中 集中 集中 集中精力比赛
You gotta get your, get your, get your, get your head in the game
来 集中 集中精力比赛
Come on, get my, get my head in the game
你需要集中 集中 集中 集中精力比赛
You gotta get your, get your, get your, get your head in the game
我需要集中 集中精力比赛
I gotta get my, get my head in the game
你需要集中 集中 集中 集中精力比赛
You gotta get your, get your, get your, get your head in the game
-什么队？-野猫队！
-What team? -Wildcats!
野猫队！
Wildcats!
集中精力比赛吧！
Get your head in the game!
唔！
Whoo!
嗯 看来你认识特洛伊·波顿
So, it seemed like you knew Troy Bolton.
不是 他只是带我转转
Not really. He was just showing me around.
嗯 特洛伊通常不和新同学搭话
Well, Troy usually doesn't interact with new students.
哦 为什么不？
Uh, why not?
因为他无时无刻总是想着篮球
-Uh, why not? -It's pretty much basketball 24/7 with him.
-应该是派（圆周率）分之16
-That should be 16 over pi...
你说什么？ 蒙特兹同学
Yes, Miss Montez?
对不起 我只是...
I'm sorry, I was just... Uh...
第二等式应该是派分之16？
Shouldn't the second equation read 16 over pi?
派分之16？不太可能
16 over pi? That's quite impossible.
我接受你的更正
I stand corrected.
哦...欢迎你
Oh... and welcome aboard.
-一会见 -好
-Catch you later, guys. -OK.
特洛伊·波顿在看报名单
Troy Bolton was looking at our audition list.
又一次？
Again?
他和新来的女孩
He was hanging around with that new girl
一起转来看过了
and they were both looking at the list.
她有些怪
There's something freaky about her.
她说她从哪里来？
Where did she say she's from?
哦！爱因斯坦
Wow! An Einsteinette.
你怎么认定
So why do you think
她对音乐剧感兴趣？
she's interested in our musical?
我不确定
I'm not sure that she is.
我们不需要担心业余的
And we needn't concern ourselves with amateurs.
但 确认一下没坏处
But... there is no harm in making certain
盖比瑞拉的来校的欢迎活动是...
that Gabriella's welcome to school activities that are...
嗯 适合她
...well, appropriate for her.
而且...
After all...
她喜欢派（圆周率）
...she loves pi.
金色！再多些！
Gold! More gold!
刷 刷！开始！
Paint, paint! Let's go!
回答是好！
-The answer is yes!
呃？
Huh?
学校的全能队伍
Our scholastic decathlon team
下周又第一次比赛
has its first competition next week,
当然有你的位置
and there is certainly a spot for you.
这是从哪里来的？
Where did those come from?
不是你放到我柜子里的吗？
Didn't you put them in my locker?
当然不是
Of course not.
嗯 我们欢迎你来我们队伍
Well, we'd love to have you on our team.
我们每天放学都开会
We meet almost every day after school.
我必需跟上这里的学习进度
I need to catch up on the curriculum here
之后才会考虑加入社团
before I think about joining any clubs.
嗯 多好的熟悉环境的方法呀
Well, what a perfect way to get caught up.
和学校最聪明的人交流
Meeting with the smartest kids in school.
多么慷慨的承诺 泰勒
What a generous offer, Taylor.
来吧？
Please?
今天留了这么多新面孔
So many new faces in detention today.
我希望你别把它成为习惯
I hope you don't make a habit of it,
不过戏剧一向欢迎帮手加入
but the drama club can always use an extra hand.
那我们就在工作的时候
And while we are working,
来处理那个越来越严重的手机问题
let us probe the mounting evils of cell phones.
来 伙计们 集合
Come on, guys, huddle up!
我们还有两周到重大的比赛
We got two weeks to the big game.
特洛伊和查德在哪里？
Where's Troy and Chad?
别要我再问一遍
Don't make me ask again.
-特洛伊和查德在哪里?! -留堂
-Where's Troy and Chad?! - Detention.
也许最可恨的滥用手机的例子
Perhaps the most heinous example of cell-phone abuse
就是在剧院
is ringing in the theater.
多么野蛮
What temerity!
剧院是艺术的圣殿
The theater is a temple of art.
我的队伍在哪里 达布丝？
Where's my team, Darbus?
这两个人在这树上做什么？
What the heck are those two doing in a tree?
这是犯错和惩罚 波顿
It's called crime and punishment, Bolton.
一个宝贵的充满创造的丰饶角饰
-A precious cornucopia of creative energy.
另外 接近艺术可以净化心灵
Besides, proximity to the arts is cleansing for the soul.
我们能谈谈吗？
Can we have a talk, please?
你们俩 去体育馆 现在！
And you two, in the gym, now!
如果他们留堂来刷道具
If they have to paint sets for detention,
他们可以晚上做 不是练习时间
they could do it tonight, not during practice.
如果是演出者
If these were theater performers,
你能要求特殊待遇吗？
would you seek special treatment?
达布丝 我们只有几天时间就要进行
Darbus, we are days away from
年度最重要的比赛
our biggest game of the year.
而我们 波顿 也正忙着准备
And we, Bolton, are in the midst of our auditions
冬季音乐剧的试镜！
for our winter musicale as well!
这个学校不只有
This school is about more than
邋遢的男孩
just young men in baggy shorts
进攻达阵！
flinging balls for touchdowns!
投篮！他们打的是篮球
Baskets! They shoot baskets.
别吵了 听着
Stop! Guys, listen,
你们争论这事
you've been having this argument
从你们俩来的那天就开始吵个不停
since the day you both started teaching here.
带着同一批学生的老师
one student body,
同一的教职工！
one faculty!
这点应该都同意吧?
Can we not agree on that?
教练 校队状况如何？
So, Coach, how's the team lookin'?
特洛伊把他们组织起来了
Troy got 'em whipped into shape?
我们是同一所学校
We are one school,
哦！
Oh!
西部高中骑士队击败我们
West High Knights have knocked us
已经连续三年了
out of the playoffs three years running,
现在我们就差一场比赛
and now we are one game
从他们那里夺回冠军了！
away from taking that championship back from 'em!
现在是我们表现的时候
It's time to make our stand.
队伍就是你们
The team is you.
你们就是队伍
You are the team.
队伍不会存在
And this team does not exist
除非你们每个人都
unless each and every one of you
集中精神在我们的目标上 清楚吗？
is fully focused on our goal. Am I clear?
-嘿 什么队？！ -野猫队！
-Hey, what team?! -Wildcats!
-什么队？-野猫队！
-What team? -Wildcats!
-什么队？ -野猫队！
-野猫队！-去比赛吧！
-Wildcats! -Get your head in the game!
我们从没通过
We've never made it
第一轮的学校全能比赛
past the first round of the scholastic decathlon.
你会是我们的答案
You could be our answered prayer.
我现在集中精力
I'm focusing on
在我的学习上
my studies this semester,
帮我妈妈整理新房子
and help my mom get the new house organized.
也许明年吧
Maybe next year.
你认为特洛伊·波顿怎么样？
What do you know about Troy Bolton?
我不是那方面的专家
I'm not an expert on that particular sub-species,
可是
however,
除非你和啦啦队说
unless you speak cheerleader,
"噢 天啊！
as in, "Oh, my gosh!
特洛伊·波顿是不是很性感啊？"
Isn't Troy Bolton just the hottie super-bum?"
特洛伊？嗯
Troy? Hmm.
噢 他太棒了
Oh, he's so beautiful.
呵呵 明白我的意思？
Ha-ha. See what I mean?
我不知道如何与啦啦队交流
I don't know how to speak cheerleader.
我们存在不同的世界里
We exist in an alternate universe to Troy the basketball boy.
和篮球青年特洛伊
to Troy the basketball boy.
你没试图了解他？
Have you tried to get to know him?
看看这里的潜规则
Watch how it works tomorrow
明天你和我们一起吃饭
when you have lunch with us.
除非你宁愿和啦啦队
Unless you'd rather sit with the cheerleaders
一起讨论修指甲
and discuss firm nail beds.
我可不关心指甲的事情
My nail beds are history.
姐妹！
Sister!
我还是不理解留堂的事
Still don't understand this detention thing.
是我的错
It was my fault.
-对不起 -场地那边
-Sorry, Dad. -Cross court.
达布丝会想尽办法找我麻烦
Darbus will take any opportunity to bust my chops.
也包括你
That includes yours too.
嗨 爸爸？
Hey, Dad?
你曾有过做新的尝试
Did you ever want to try something new,
但是担心你的朋友的想法吗？
but were afraid of what your friends think?
像是说左路进攻？
Like, going left?
你没问题的
You're doing fine.
嗯...不
Well... no.
我是说 如果你尝试全新的
I mean, what if you wanna try something really new
完全是个灾难
and it's a total disaster
你所有的朋友嘲笑你
and all your friends laugh at you.
也许他们不是你真正的朋友
Maybe they're not your friends.
这是我今天对队员们讲的
That was my whole point about team today.
你们要互相照看 你是队长
You gotta look out for each other. You're the leader.
-爸爸 我是说...-下周比赛
-Dad I mean talk...-There's gonna
有大学球探会过来
be college scouts at our game next week.
知道奖学金有多重要吗?
Know what a scholarship is worth these days?
-很重要 -没错 特洛伊 专心点
-A lot. -Yeah. Focus, Troy, come on.
哦
Whoo.
这是给你的
Just something for you.
我期望我们都吸取了
I expect we all learned
昨天的教训 对吗？
our homeroom manners yesterday, people, correct?
如果没有 我们还有更衣室要粉刷
If not, we have some dressing rooms that need painting.
现在 宣布几件事情
Now, a few announcements.
今天上午的自习时间
This morning during free period
独唱和对唱
both single and pairs.
我会呆到中午
I will be in the theater until noon
为了你们大胆地展现
for those of you bold enough to extend
你们的创新精神
the wingspan of your creative spirit.
有音乐剧的试镜
will be your chance for the musicale auditions,
什么时候她会老调重谈？
When's she due back on the mother ship?
讨论莎士比亚的重要性...
Discussing the importance of Shakespeare...
- 怎么了？ - 什么事？
- What's up, man? - What's up?
队员们会在自习时间去体育馆
The team's hitting the gym during free period.
我们练什么？
What should we run?
我去不了 我得赶作业
I can't make it. I gotta catch up on some homework.
什么？嘿 这才是回来的第二天
What? Hello, it's only the second day back.
我都没落下作业
I'm not even behind on homework yet.
我从学前班开始就落下作业
And I've been behind on homework since preschool.
太荒谬了 一会儿见
That's hilarious. I'll catch you later.
作业？不可能
Homework? There's no way.
-你好吗？ -随便转转？
- How's it going? - Just hanging out?
-高兴见到你 -他搞什么？
- Good to see you. - What's he doing?
你好吗？
How's it going, man?
超近路
Short-cut.
我要迟到了
I'm late for class.
好 就放那里
That's good, just leave it here.
这是展现艺术家
This is where the true
真切情感的地方
expression of the artist is realized.
通过演员的表演
Where inner truth is revealed
展现内部的真实...
through the actor's journey...
是手机在响吗？
-Was that a cell phone?
是我的吗？
Is it mine?
不 老师 是警告铃
-No, ma'am. That was the warning bell.
啊！
Ah!
要参加试镜的人要明白
Those wishing to audition must understand
时间的紧迫
that time is of the essence.
我们有许多的角色
We have many roles to cast
下周是最后一次
and final callbacks will be next week.
首先 你们要先唱一段
First, you will sing a few bars
我会评价你是否
and I will give you a sense of whether or not
适合剧场的召唤
the theater is your calling.
最好现在直接听我的
Better to hear it from me now
而不是一会儿从你朋友那里知道
than from your friends later.
我们的作曲 凯尔西·尼尔森
Our composer, Kelsi Nielson,
会陪你们
will accompany you
开始？
Shall we?
难以置信我竟从未发现
It's hard to believe that I couldn't see
你一直在我旁边
That you were always right beside me
从预演到最后 协助大家彩排
and be available for rehearsals prior to callbacks.
这种感觉前所未有
This feeling like no other
我要你了解
I want you to know
哦 谢谢 下一个！
Uh-huh. Yes, thank you. Next!
难以置信
It's hard to believe
我竟从未花现
That I couldn't sneeze... see
你一直在我旁边
That you were always right there next to... beside me
阿伦 我敬佩你的勇气
Alan, I admire your pluck.
关于你的歌...
- As to your singing... ...like no other
你的领带很好 下一个！
That's a wonderful tie you're wearing. Next!
难以置信我竟从未发现
It's hard to believe that I couldn't see
你一直在我旁边
That you were always there beside me
这种感觉前所未有
This feeling's like no other
我要你了解
I want you to know
哦...停吧
Uh... stop.
寂寞之情萦绕不去...
so lonely before I finally found
直到我找到梦中人
What I've been looking...
为了...
for...
啊...辛蒂
Ah... Cindra.
多大的勇气来唱
What courage to pursue a note
自然界没有的音符
that has not been accessed in the natural world.
好啊！
Bravo! Brava!
春季音乐剧吧
Perhaps the spring musicale.
难以置信
- It's hard to believe
我竟从未发现 -未发现
that I could not see -Can't see
-你一直在我旁边 -我旁边
- That you were right beside me - Beside me
-我以为自己孤单寂寞 -孤单寂寞
- Thought I was alone - Alone
-没有人可以拥抱 -可以拥抱
- With no one to hold - To hold
-但你一直都在我身边 -我身边
- But you were right beside me - Beside me
嗯 这
Well, that was just...
太恶心了...看心理医生去
...very disturbing. Go see a counselor. Uhh.
下一个！
Next!
嗨！
Hey!
你决定报名参加面试了？
So you decided to sign up for something?
呃...没 你呢？
Uh... No. You?
没
No.
嗯...你为什么躲在拖把后面？
Um... why are you hiding behind a mop?
你朋友不知道你在这里 对吗？
Your friends don't know you're here, right?
对
Right.
谢谢 下一个
Thank you. Next.
达布丝老师有点....刻薄
Miss Darbus is a little... harsh.
野猫队的明星害怕了？
- The Wildcat superstar's afraid?
不！我不怕 我...
No! I'm not afraid, I...
我就是有些...恐惧
I'm just... scared.
我也是...经常
Me too... usually.
关于主角明尼和阿诺德
And for the lead roles of Minnie and Arnold
我们只有一对人报名
we only have one couple signed up.
夏培和瑞安
Sharpay and Ryan,
我想也许对你们有益处
I think it might be useful for you
给你们一个感觉
to give us a sense of why
我们为什么来到这个圣殿
we gather in this hallowed hall.
什么调？
What key?
哦 我们让自己的钢琴师
Oh, we had our rehearsal pianist
录了音
do an arrangement.
噢
Oh.
来！
Go!
难以置信
It's hard to believe
我竟从未发现
that I couldn't see
你一直在我身旁
You were always there beside me
没有人可以拥抱
with no one to hold
但你一直在我身旁
But you were always right beside me
这种感觉前所未有
This feeling's like no other
我要你知道
I want you to know
我以为自己孤单寂寞
Thought I was alone
我从未遇见过
I've never had someone
像你如此了解我的人
that knows me like you do
你是如此了解我
The way you do
我从未遇见过
I've never had someone
像你这么好的人
as good for me as you
没有人比得上你
No one like you
找到梦中之人前
So lonely before I finally found
我有多么寂寞
What I've been looking for
被人看见 被人听见
So good to be seen,
感觉真是美好
so good to be heard
一个字都不必说
Don't have to say a word
长久以来 我迷失自己
For so long I was lost,
能被你找到真好
so good to be found
我喜欢有你在身旁
I'm lovin' having you around
这感觉什么都比不上
This feeling's like no other
我从未遇见过
I've never had someone
像你如此了解我的人
that knows me like you do
你是如此了解我
The way you do
我从没遇过
I've never had someone
我要你知道
I want you to know
像你这么好的人
as good for me as you
没有人比得上你
No one like you
找到梦中之人前
So lonely before I finally found
我有多么寂寞
What I've been looking for
嘟-嘟-嘟
Do-do-do
嘟 嘟-嘟-嘟 嘟-嘟
Do do-do-do do-do
哦 哇-哦-哦-哦
Oh, whoa-oh-oh-oh
嘟-嘟-嘟
Do-do-do-do
嘟 嘟-嘟-嘟 嘟-嘟
Do do-do-do do-do
哦 哇-哦-哦-哦
Oh, whoa-oh-oh-oh
我告诉你不要跳爵士步
I told you not to do the jazz squares.
那是人们喜欢的
It's a crowd favorite.
人人都喜欢爵士步
Everybody loves a good jazz square.
嗯...
Well...
有没有候补报名？
Are there any last-minute sign-ups?
别灰心
Don't be discouraged.
戏剧社不仅需要歌手
The theater club needs more than singers.
还需要粉丝
It needs fans too.
买票！
Buy tickets!
哦 对
Oh, actually,
如果你们要用那首歌
if you do the part with that particular song,
节奏应该要慢一些...
I imagined it much slow...
如果我们唱？
If we do the part?
PS: Sondheim 桑德海姆 (美国著名作曲作词家 号称概念音乐剧鼻祖)
凯尔西 我的小作曲家
Kelsi, my sawed-off Sondheim,
我主演了17部校园音乐剧
Kelsi, my sawed-off Sondheim, I've been in 17 school productions.
有多少你的作品被选用了？
How many of your compositions have been selected?
这是第一个
This would be the first.
这告诉我们什么？
Which tells us what?
呃 我需要为你写更多的独唱？
Uh. That I need to write you more solos?
不 这告诉我们你没有资格提出
No. It tells us that you do not offer
任何建议 意见或评论
direction, suggestion or commentary.
而你应该表示感激
And you should be thankful
我和瑞安让你的音乐
that me and Ryan can lift your music
得到大家的认可
out of its obscurity.
明白吗?
-Are we clear?
是 夫人 我是说 夏培小姐
Yes, ma'am. I mean, Sharpay.
很荣幸和你交谈
Nice talking to you.
还有没有报名的？
Any last-minute sign-ups?
我们应该走了
We should go.
没有？好 结束
No? Good. Done.
我想试镜 达布丝老师
I'd like to audition, Miss Darbus.
在剧场 时间就是一切 年轻人
Timeliness means something in the world of theater, young lady.
单人试镜老早就结束了
The individual auditions are long long over
而且也没有其他人和你搭档
and there are simply no other pairs.
我和她唱
I'll sing with her.
特洛伊·波顿？
Troy Bolton?
你的运动伙伴
Where is your sports posse
不管叫什么 在哪儿呢
or whatever it's called?
队员
Team.
呃
Ah.
啊
Amm.
但我是一个人
But I'm here alone.
实际上 我来这里和她唱的
Actually, I'm here to sing with her.
是的 好吧
Yes, well,
对这次演出我们十分认真
we take these shows very seriously
在东部高中
here at East High.
在双人试镜时我已唱过名
I called for the pairs audition,
你没有回应
and you didn't respond.
自习时间结束了
Free period is now over.
她的嗓音非常好
She has an amazing voice.
也许下一部音乐剧吧
Perhaps the next musicale.
你就是作曲人？
So, you're a composer?
你写歌 瑞安和夏培只是唱？
You wrote the song Ryan and Sharpay just sang?
整个剧？
And the entire show?
哦 太棒了
Well, that's really cool.
我太期望其余的部分了
I can't wait to hear the rest of the show.
那么 你为什么怕瑞安和夏培？
So, why are you so afraid of Ryan and Sharpay?
-我是说 这出剧是你写的
-I mean, it is your show.
是吗？
It is?
作曲家就像是
Isn't the composer of a show
球赛中的控球员？
kind of like the playmaker in basketball?
控球员？
Playmaker?
就是让别人表现更出色的人
The one who makes everyone else look good.
没有你就没有这出戏
Without you there is no show.
你是这出戏的控球员 凯尔西
You're the playmaker here, Kelsi.
我是吗？
I am?
想不想听听
Do you wanna hear how
那首歌原本的样子
duet's supposed to sound?
难以置信
It's hard to believe
我竟从未发现
that I couldn't see
你一直在我身旁
You were always there beside me
我以为自己孤单寂寞
Thought I was alone
没有人可以拥抱
with no one to hold
但你一直在我身旁
But you were always right beside me
这种感觉前所未有
This feeling's like no other
我要你知道
I want you to know
我从未遇见过
That I've never had someone
像你如此了解我的人
that knows me like you do
你是如此了解我
The way you do
我从未遇见过
And I've never had someone
像你这么好的人
as good for me as you
没有人比得上你
No one like you
找到梦中之人前
So lonely before I finally found
我有多么寂寞
What I've been looking for
哦-哦-哦
Ooh-ooh-ooh
喔
Wow.
太好了
That's nice.
波顿 蒙特兹 你们进复试了
Bolton, Montez - you have a callback.
凯尔西 给他们第二幕的曲子
Kelsi, give them the duet from the second act.
-好好准备 -好
-Work on it with them. -All right.
要是你们想要排练的话
If you guys wanna rehearse,
自习课与放学后我经常在这里
I'm usually here during free period and after school,
甚至生物课的时候
and even sometimes during biology class.
你们可以任何时间来
You can come and rehearse anytime.
或来我家吃早饭
Or come to my house for breakfast.
我有钢琴 我们可以在那里练习
I have a piano, we can rehearse there.
放学后 上学前
After school, before school
只要有空 篮球课后
-whatever works. After basketball class...
什么？
What?
复试？！
Callback?!
啊！
Aah!
"阿诺德和米妮的复试
"Callback for roles Arnold and Minnie
在下周四下午三点半
next Thursday, 3:30pm.
瑞安和夏培·埃文斯
Ryan and Sharpay Evans,
盖比瑞拉·蒙特兹和特洛伊·波顿"
Gabriella Montez and Troy Bolton."
这是开玩笑吗？
Is this some kind of joke?
他们都没去试镜！
They didn't even audition!
也许我们被整了？
Maybe we're being punked?
什么？
What?
也许我们正在被拍摄
Maybe we're being filmed right now.
也许我们会见到阿斯顿！
Maybe we'll get to meet Ashton!
哦 闭嘴 瑞安！
Oh, shut up, Ryan!
怎么了？
What's wrong?
什么？
What ?
噢
Uhh!
她怎么敢报名！
How dare she sign up!
我选了我更衣室的颜色
I picked out the colors for my dressing room.
她都没征得
She hasn't even asked
我们的允许就加入戏剧社
our permission to join the drama club.
得有人告诉她这里的规则
Someone's gotta tell her the rules.
没错
Exactly.
什么规则？
And what are the rules?
噢！
Ohh!
但我内心翻腾
But inside I am stirring
奇怪的事情正在发生
something strange is occurring
我得分享这个秘密
It's a secret I need to share
敞开心门 发掘你内心的欲望
Open up, dig way down deep
我喜欢说唱音乐 我喜欢搞破坏！
Hip-hop is my passion. I love to pop and lock and jam and break!
这合法吗？
Is that even legal?
别再说了
Not another peep!
就是跳舞 我想这比作业有意思
It's just dancing. I think it's cooler than homework.
不 不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no! No, no, no
做你熟悉的事情就好
Stick to the stuff you know
让事物维持原状比较好
It is better by far to keep things as they are
别破坏现状 不..
Don't mess with the flow, no, no
维持现状就好
Stick to the status quo
听好了 我要宣布我真切的渴望
Listen well, I'm ready to tell about a need that I cannot deny
这美妙的感觉无法言喻
Dude, there's no explanation for this awesome sensation
我已准备好要大声说出
But I'm ready to let it fly
让大家听听你的想法
Speak your mind and you'll be heard
如果特洛伊 想唱歌 我也参与
If Troy wants to be a singer, then I'm coming clean.
我弹大提琴
- I play the cello!
好啊！那是什么？
Awesome! What is it?
电锯吗?
A saw!
不 那是大型的提琴!
No, dude, it's like, a giant violin!
别再说了
Not another peep!
你要穿服装吗？
Do you have to wear a costume?
西服领带
Coat and tie.
不 不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no! No, no, no
做你熟悉的事情
Stick to the stuff you know
想耍酷 就要遵守简单的规则
If you wanna be cool, follow one simple rule
别破坏现状 不..
Don't mess with the flow, no, no
维持现状就好
Stick to the status quo
不 不 不
No, no, no
做你熟悉的事情
Stick to the stuff you know
让事物维持原状比较好
It is better by far to keep things as they are
别破坏现状 不..
Don't mess with the flow, no, no
维持现状就好
Stick to the status quo
这不是我想要的
This is not what I want
也不是我所计划的
This is not what I planned
我必须说
And I just gotta say
我真的不懂
I do not understand
有些地方真的..
Something is really
不太对劲 真的大有问题
-Something's not right-Really wrong
我们得让事情恢复正常
And we've gotta get things back where they belong
一定办得到-我要演奏
-We can do it-Gotta play
-做你熟悉的事情 -我们办得到的
-Stick with what you know-We can do it
-嘻哈万岁-她必须退出
-Hip-hop hooray-She has got to go
-我们办得到的 -焦糖布丁
-We can do it-Creme Brulee
别大声说话
Keep your voice down low
-别发出任何声音..-不
-Not another peep-No
-大家安静-不
-Not another word-No
-不准出声音-不
-Not another sound-No
大家安静!
Everybody quiet!
为什么大家都看你？
Why is everybody staring at you?
- 不是我 是你 -因为试镜？
- Not me, you. - Because of the callbacks?
我受不了别人盯着我
I can't have people staring at me. I can't.
不 不 不
No, no, no
做你熟悉的事情就好
Stick to the stuff you know
想耍酷 就要遵守简单的规则
If you want to be cool, follow one simple rule
别破坏现状 不..
Don't mess with the flow, no, no
维持现状就好
Stick to the status quo
不 不 不
No, no, no
做你熟悉的事情
Stick to the stuff you know
让事物维持原状比较好
It is better by far to keep things as they are
别破坏现状 不..
Don't mess with the flow, no, no
维持现状..维持现状..
Stick to the status stick to the status
维持现状..
Stick to the status quo
啊
Aah!
对不起
I am so sorry.
太戏剧化了 是
-Too much drama. - Yeah.
怎么回事？
What is going on here?
看看 盖比瑞拉把午餐扣在我身上！
Look at this! That Gabriella girl just dumped her lunch on me!
故意的！是他们破坏音乐剧的计划的一部分
On purpose! It's all part of their plan to ruin our musical.
你不会想淌这场浑水的
You do not want to get into that, man.
特洛伊和他的人明显在幕后
And Troy and his basketball robots are obviously behind it.
你为什么认为他试镜了？
Why do you think he auditioned?
在你努力为音乐剧工作后
After all the hard work you've put into this show.
这不正确
It just doesn't seem right.
-怎么了? -怎么了? 呃 看看...
- What's up? - What's up? Oh, let's see...
你错过了自习时间的练习
You missed free-period workout
去试镜可恨的音乐剧
to audition for a heinous musical.
现在突然间大家都开始自我表白
And now suddenly people are confessing.
泽克 泽克竟然喜欢烘培,还做焦糖布丁
Yeah, and Zeke. Zeke is baking... creme brulee.
那是什么？
What's that?
哦 是一种表层涂上焦糖的奶冻
Oh, a creamy custard with a caramelized surface.
-非常好吃喔! -泽克,闭嘴!
-It's really satisfying. - Shut up, Zeke!
看...看到发生什么了吗？
Look... do you see what's happening here, man?
我们的队伍因为你唱歌分裂了
Our team is coming apart because of your singing thing.
就连那些怪人和书呆子都
Even the drama geeks and the brainiacs suddenly
自以为有资格..跟我们说话
think that they can......talk to us.
看 滑板的人都混在一起
-Look, the skater dudes are mingling. - Yo!
突然间 人们都认为
Suddenly people think that
他们能做些其他的事了
they can do other stuff.
不是他们本身的事
Stuff that's not their stuff.
下周末就是决赛了
You're thinking about show tunes,
你却在想着歌曲的曲调
when we've got a playoff game next week.
噢
Whoa!
噢  注意！
-Ooh! -Heads up!
好了 摊牌吧
- All right. Cards on the table right now. - Huh?
我惩罚你的球星们留校
You're tweaked because I put your stars in detention
所以你才报复我吗?
and now you're getting even.
你在说什么 达布丝？
What are you talking about, Darbus?
你那明星儿子跑来参加试镜
Your all-star son turned up at my audition.
现在 我会给他公平的机会
Now, I give every student an even chance,
这是剧院里的崇高的传统
which is a long and honorable tradition in the theater.
这些事你是无法理解的
Something that you wouldn't understand.
但 他如果想在我的圣殿里
But, if he is planning some sort of practical joke
计划捣什么乱...
in my chapel of the arts...
特洛伊都不会唱歌
Troy doesn't even sing.
噢 你可错了
Oh, well, you're wrong about that.
但我不会允许
But I will not allow
我的闪亮之城音乐剧成为闹剧
my Twinkle Town musicale to be made into farce.
- 闪亮之城？-看？我就知道！
- Twinkle Town? - See? I knew it!
-嘿... -我就知道！
- Hey... -I knew it!
好像很适合冬天 祝你好运！
Sounds like a winner. Good luck on Broadway!
夏培真的很生气吗？我说了对不起
Is Sharpay really, really mad at me? I said I was sorry.
看 从幼儿园开始就没人比夏培音乐好
Look, no one has beaten out Sharpay for a musical since kindergarten.
我没要和她比
I wasn't trying to beat anyone out.
我们都没有试镜 只是唱了唱
We didn't even audition, we were just singing.
夏培不会信的
You won't convince Sharpay of that.
如果她能自己一起演罗米欧和朱莉叶
If that girl could play both Romeo and Juliet,
她弟弟都没有机会
her own brother would be aced out.
我告诉你就这么发生了 但我喜欢
I told you it just happened, but I liked it.
非常的
A lot.
你感到过就好像你心中有另一个人
Did you ever feel like there's a whole other person inside you
想夺路而出？
just looking for a way to come out?
没有
Not really. No.
我们走吧
Let's go.
嗨 夏培 呃
Hey, Sharpay,Uh
我想因为特洛伊·波顿会在你的演出里...
Hey, Sharpay, I thought since Troy Bolton's gonna be in your show...
特洛伊·波顿不会参与演出的
Troy Bolton is not in my show.
好...我想也许
OK, um... well, I thought maybe
你什么时间可以来看我打球
you could watch me play ball sometime.
我宁愿把笔插到眼里
- I'd rather stick pins in my eyes.
不会不舒服吗？
Wouldn't that be awfully uncomfortable?
消失吧 高个
Evaporate, tall person!
我会做甜点！
I bake!
如果有帮助的话
If that helps.
喔！这上面像个个丛林
Wow! It's like a jungle up here.
对 就像那个咖啡厅
Yeah, just like that cafeteria.
我刚刚丢尽了脸
Well, I just humiliated myself into the next century.
-不！算了 -这是你的小天地？
- No! Come on. - So this is your private hideout?
嗯 感谢科学社
Yeah. Thanks to the science club.
意思是我的伙伴们不知道这地方
Which means my buddies don't know it exists.
你把学校连在了一起 对吗 特洛伊？
You pretty much have the school wired, don't you, Troy?
好像学校里所有人都想和你做朋友
Seems to me like everyone on campus wants to be your friend.
除非我们输了
Unless we lose.
嗯 我想做教练的儿子不容易
Well, I'm sure it's tricky being the coach's son.
我想使我更努力训练
Makes me practice a little harder, I guess.
我不知道他会怎么说唱歌的事
I don't know what he'll say about the singing.
- 你担心了？ -我父母的朋友总是说
- You worried? - My parents' friends are always saying,
"你儿子是打篮球的料 你一定很骄傲"
"Your son's the basketball guy. You must be so proud."
有时候我不想做"打篮球的料"
Sometimes I don't wanna be the "basketball guy."
我只想做个普通人 知道吗？
I just wanna be a guy. You know?
我昨天看到你对待凯尔西的态度
I saw the way you treated Kelsi at the audition yesterday.
你朋友了解那个人吗？
Do your friends know that guy?
他们 我是决策人
To them, I'm the playmaker dude.
他们不完全了解你 特洛伊
They don't know enough about you, Troy.
在其他学校我是怪怪的数学女孩
At my other schools I was the freaky math girl.
来这里很好...成为我想成为的任何人
It's cool coming here and being... anyone I wanna be.
当我和你唱歌的时候 我感觉像...一个女孩
When I was singing with you I just felt like... a girl.
你看起来也很像
You even look like one, too.
记得在幼儿园
Remember in kindergarten
你遇到个孩子 你什么都不了解
how you'd meet a kid and know nothing about them,
十秒后 你们就像好朋友一样玩了
then ten seconds later you play like you're best friends
因为你只要做自己就好了
because you didn't have to be anything but yourself.
-对 -和你唱歌就像那样
- Yeah. - Singing with you felt like that.
嗯...我从没想过唱歌 确实这样
Well, uh... I never thought about singing. That's for sure.
直到遇到你
Till you.
那么你还想继续试镜？
So you really wanna do the callbacks?
嘿 就叫我怪怪的试镜男孩好了
Hey, just call me freaky callback boy.
你很酷 特洛伊
You're a cool guy, Troy.
可不是你朋友们想的那些原因
But not for the reasons your friends think.
谢谢带我来这个秘密的小天地
And thanks for showing me your top-secret hiding place.
就像幼儿园
Like kindergarten.
我们展翅翱翔 飞行
We're soarin', flyin'...
你们无从知道那感觉
You can bet there's nothin'
像是走在只有张安全网的钢索上
but net when I am in a zone and on a roll
但我还是得说出
But I got a confession
我的秘密渴望
my own secret obsession
我再也无法忍耐
And it's making me lose control
大家靠过来
Everybody gather 'round
挣脱...
Breaking...
如果特洛伊 能讲他的秘密，我也可以讲我的
If Troy can tell his secret, then I can tell mine.
其实我爱烘培
I bake.
什么？
What?
我爱烘培 果馅饼 烤饼 苹果布丁
I love to bake! Strudels, scones, even apple pandowdy.
空间不断将我们隔开
Creating space between us
别再说了
Not another sound
有一天我希望做出焦糖布丁
Someday I hope to make the perfect creme brulee.
不 不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no! No, no, no
做你熟悉的事情就好
Stick to the stuff you know
想耍酷就遵守简单的规则
If you wanna be cool follow one simple rule
别破坏现状,不..
Don't mess with the flow no, no
维持现状就好
Stick to the status quo
看着我 你看到什么?
Look at me and what do you see?
世界第一的聪明才智
Intelligence beyond compare
没有什么浩瀚星辰
There's not a star in heaven
是我们...
that we...
飞行
Flyin'
没有什么浩瀚星辰
There's not a star in heaven
是我们触不到的
that we can't reach
来 伙计们 快些！
Let's go, guys! Make it sharp!
向胸部 胸部 来！传球！
To the chest,To the chest， come on! Pop it!
来 伙计们 移动！开始！
Come on, guys. Step with it! Let's go!
来 移动！开始！
Come on, move it! Let's go!
来！集中！集中精力在比赛！
Come on, guys, focus! Focus! Get your head in the game!
移动！
Move it!
- 你看到 特洛伊？ - 没有...教练
- You seen Troy? - No... Coach.
来 继续！
Again, let's go!
好了 洗澡去吧 好防守 比赛里见
That's it, guys. Let's hit the showers. Good hustle. Let's see that in the game.
我...我想我会呆会儿 练罚篮
I, uh... think I'm gonna stay a while. Work on some free throws.
因为你错过了训练
Since you missed practice,
我认为你的队伍今天要看你的努力
I think your team deserves a little effort from you today.
喔 这是你真正的舞台
Wow. So this is your real stage.
对 我想你可以这么说
Yeah. I guess you could call it that.
或一个有味道的体育馆
Or just a smelly gym.
哇
Whoa!
别告诉我你也擅长篮球
Don't tell me you're good at hoops, too.
知道吗 我曾在联赛决赛里得了41分
You know, I once scored 41 points at a league championship game.
-不会吧 -嗯-哼
- No way. -Mm-hm.
而且同一天
And the same day,
我发明了太空梭和微波炉爆米花
I invented the space shuttle and microwave popcorn.
微波炉爆米花 有意思
Oh! Microwave popcorn. Ha-ha. Funny.
-我在和凯尔西练习 -我也是 顺便说
- I've been rehearsing with Kelsi. - Me, too. And, by the way,
我错过了训练
I missed practice.
那么如果我被赶出队 你良心会受谴责
So if I get kicked off the team it'll be on your conscience.
- 嘿 又不是我叫你... -盖比瑞拉 别跑
- Hey, I wasn't the one who told you... - Gabriella, chill.
嗨 这是走步 不 这是严重走步
Hey, that's traveling. No, that's really bad traveling.
小姐！对不起 这是非公开的训练
Miss! I'm sorry, this is a closed practice.
- 爸 别这样 训练结束了 -还有一个队员没走呢
- Dad,come on，practice is over. - Not till the last player leaves.
-队里的规定 -对不起
- Team rule. - Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
- 爸爸 这是盖比瑞拉·蒙特兹 -哦 你留堂的伙伴
- Dad, this is Gabriella Montez. - Ah, your detention buddy.
再见 特洛伊
I’ll see you later, Troy.
很高兴见到你 波顿教练
Nice meeting you, Coach Bolton.
我也是 蒙特兹
You as well, Miss Montez.
爸爸 留堂是我的错 不是她
Dad, detention was my fault, not hers.
你三年没错过训练 直到她出现...
You haven't missed practice in three years. That girl shows up...
她叫盖比瑞拉 她很好
That girl is named Gabriella. She's very nice.
使你错过训练是她不好 至少对我讲
Helping you miss practice doesn't make her very nice. Not in my book.
-或你的队伍 -爸爸 不是她的问题
- Or your team's. - Dad, she's not a problem.
-她只是个女孩 -但你不只是个男孩  特洛伊
-She's just a girl. -But you're not just a guy, Troy.
你是队伍的领袖
You're the team leader.
你的影响不只对队伍而且是对整个学校
What you do affects not only this team, but the entire school.
除非你全心投入 我们下周不会赢
And without you completely focused, we're not gonna win next week.
冠军赛 -不经常有
The championship games - they don't come along all the time.
-这是特别的 -对 很多事是特别的 爸爸
-They're something special. -Yeah, a lot of things are special, Dad.
但你是球队领袖...不是歌手 对吗？
But you're a playmaker... not a singer, right?
你没想过我两个都是吗？
Did you ever think maybe I could be both?
-什么？ -我们走
-What? -Let's go.
是什么魔法让那个高智商的女孩
What spell has this elevated-IQ temptress girl cast
突然使你想参加音乐剧？
that suddenly makes you wanna be in a musical?
看 我就是做了 谁在乎？
Look, I just did it. Who cares?
谁在乎？你最忠诚的朋友？
Who cares? How about your most loyal best friend?
-安静 丹弗斯 -是他 福萨老师 不是我
-Quiet in here, Mr. Danforth. - It's him, Miss Falsaff, not me.
看 你是篮球少年 不是音乐剧歌手
Look, you're a hoops dude, not a musical singer person.
你看过麦克 克莱福德在麦片盒子上吗？
Have you seen Michael Crawford on a cereal box?
-谁是麦克 克莱福德？ -正是我的重点
-Who's Michael Crawford? - Exactly my point.
他是百老汇的歌剧幽灵
He was the Phantom of the Opera on Broadway.
现在 我妈妈 她看那歌剧27遍
Now my mom, she's seen that musical 27 times,
而且把麦克 克莱福德的照片放到冰箱里
and put Michael Crawford's picture in our refrigerator.
对 不在外面 在里面
Yeah, not on it, in it.
我的观点是 如果你打篮球 你会在麦片盒子上
So my point is, if you play basketball, you're gonna end up on the cereal box.
为什么在冰箱里？
Why in her refrigerator?
她的一个疯狂的减肥计划
One of her crazy diet ideas.
我从不想理解女性的看法
I won't attempt to understand the female mind.
那是个复杂难懂的领域
It's foreign territory.
如果你做音乐剧 你会在我妈妈的冰箱里
If you're in musicals, you'll end up in my mom's refrigerator.
你怎么能希望我们集中精力在比赛上
How can you expect the rest of us to be focused on a game
如果你在其他地方
if you're off somewhere
唱什么内衣 "闪亮之城"？
in leotards singing "Twinkle Town"?
没有人说什么内衣
No one said anything about leotards.
还没有 但你等等看
Not yet, my friend, but just you wait.
你看 我们需要你 队长 重要时刻
Look, we need you, Captain. Big time.
-丹弗斯 -我正告诉他 福萨老师
-Mr. Danforth. - I tried to tell him, Miss Falsaff.
真累
Really tried.
有些事情不对
Something isn't right.
- 嗨 我们得谈谈 -走
-Hey, look. We need to talk. - Go.
他们一定在想
They must be trying to figure out a way
如何让特洛伊和盖比瑞拉打败我们
to make sure Troy and Gabriella beat us out.
这些人掌控着大部分学校
The jocks rule most of the school,
但如果他们使特洛伊参加音乐剧
but if they get Troy into a musical,
他们就控制了所有学生
then they've conquered the entire student body.
如果这些好学生
And if those science girls
使盖比瑞拉和特洛伊搞到一起
And if those science girls get Gabriella hooked up with Troy Bolton,
学术社就野鸡变凤凰了
the scholastic club goes from drool to cool.
瑞安 我们要从他们手中挽救音乐剧
Ryan, we need to save our show from people
那些分不清托尼奖和托尼·霍克的人
who don't know the difference between a Tony Award and Tony Hawk.
你认为那可行吗？
Do you think that'll work?
这是唯一挽救特洛伊和盖比瑞拉的方法
It's the only way to save Troy and Gabriella from themselves.
-那我们行动？ -好
-So we on? -Yeah.
- 好 我们明天就开始 -好 首先的是
-Good. So we start tomorrow then. - OK, the first thing.
- 好 我们行动   酷
-Nice. Let's go. - Cool.
我时间是7:45 山地标准时间 同步吗？
So, my watch is 7:45 Mountain Standard time. We synched?
-随便 -那么我们在12:05午餐行动
- Whatever. - Then we're on go mode for lunch, 12:05.
好  查德 行动 但我们不是霹雳娇娃 好吗？
Yes, Chad, we're a go. But we're not Charlie's Angels. OK?
我倒想 行吗？
I can dream, can't I?
"蜘蛛人" 比尔 纳存 72级
"Spider" Bill Netrine, class of '72.
他是联赛冠军赛的最有价值球员
He was the MVP in the league championship game.
萨姆 尼德尔 02级 被称为"赛米 斯拉码"
Sam Nedler, class of '02. Also known as "Sammy Slamma Jamma."
队长 联赛冠军赛的最有价值球员
Captain, MVP of the league championship team.
"霹雳手" 哈泊 哈顿 95级
The "Thunder Clap," Hap Hadden, '95.
领导野猫队连夺两届城市冠军
Led the Wildcats to back-to-back city championships.
-一个传奇 -对 传奇 所有都是
- A legend. - Yes. Legends, one and all.
但你认为他们野猫队的传奇能成为传奇是否
But do you think that any of these Wildcat legends became legends
因为参与冠军赛前的音乐剧试镜？
by getting involved in musical auditions days before the league championships?
-集中精力比赛！ -不
-Get your head in the game! - No.
这些野猫队传奇能成为传奇
These Wildcat legends became legends
因为他们从不想荣誉以外的事
because they never took their eye off the prize.
集中精力比赛！
Get your head in the game!
谁是第一个二年级就成为首发阵容的？
Who was the first sophomore ever to make starting varsity?
-特洛伊！ -谁选他作我们今年的队长的？
- Troy! - Who voted him team captain this year?
- 我们！ - 谁在周五的比赛会被打倒
- Us! - And who is gonna get their butts kicked
如果特洛伊担心试镜？
in Friday's championship game if Troy's worried about an audition?
-我们 -兄弟们 算了
-We are. - Guys, come on.
队里有12名队员 不只我
There's 12 people on this team, not just me.
12 哦 不
Just 12? Oh, no.
我想你忘了最重要的第13人
I think you're forgetting about one very important 13th member of our squad.
-我爸爸 -对 特洛伊
- My dad. - Yes, Troy.
野猫队冠军 1981级
Wildcat basketball champion, class of 1981.
冠军 父亲 现在是教练
Champion, father, and now coach.
这是与众不同的胜利传统
It's a winning tradition like no other.
从猿人到早期的武士 中世纪的骑士
From lowly Neanderthal and Cro-Magnon, to early warriors, medieval knights.
所有都是
All leading up to...
呆瓜篮球队员
...lunkhead basketball man.
许多世代以来 我们文化中对侵略过度崇拜
Yes, our culture worshiped the aggressor throughout the ages
于是产生了笨的 高估的无脑运动员
and we end up with spoiled, overpaid bonehead athletes
这就是特洛伊·波顿的世界
That is the inevitable world of Troy Bolton.
但智慧的路 才是我们要走的
But the path of the mind, the path we're on,
他们对文明毫无贡献 只会扣篮和达阵
who contribute little to civilization other than slam dunks and touchdowns.
这条路赐给了我们这些人:
ours is the path that has brought us these people:
埃莉诺·罗斯福 福瑞达·克尔 桑托·奥康纳
Eleanor Roosevelt, Frida Kahlo, Sandra Day O'Connor,
居里夫人 简·古道尔 奥普拉·温弗莉
Madame Curie, Jane Goodall, Oprah Winfrey
和其他世界名人
and so many others who the world reveres.
但 什么是...？凯尔西在等我练习
Uh, but, what is? I've got Kelsi waiting for me to rehearse.
盖比瑞拉！
Gabriella!
特洛伊 波顿代表进化的另一方
Troy Bolton represents one side of evolution.
我们这边 是受教育
And our side, the side of education and accomplishment
是文明的未来！
is the future of civilization!
这是你所应该在的一方
This is the side where you belong.
兄弟们
Guys,
如果你们不知道
if you don't know
我会投入110% 的努力在比赛里
that I'll put a 110% of my guts into that game,
那么那么就不了解我
then you don't know me.
但我们只是想...
But we just thought...
我告诉你们我怎么想
I'll tell you what I thought.
我想 你们是我的朋友
I thought that you're my friends.
一起赢 一起输 是队友
Win together, lose together, teammates.
但这女孩的出现...去唱歌
But suddenly the girl... and the singing.
嘿 我是球队的！
- Man, I'm for the team!
我是属于球队的 她只是我遇到的一个人
I've always been for the team. She's just someone I met.
好了 唱歌不算什么 只是缓解紧张
All right. The singing thing is nothing. Away to keep my nerves down.
唱歌不算什么
It means nothing to me.
你们是我的兄弟 这是我们的队伍
You're my guys and this is our team.
盖比瑞拉不重要
Gabriella is not important.
我会忘了她
I'll forget about her.
忘了试镜 我们会得到冠军
Forget the audition and we'll get that championship.
都满意了？
Everyone happy now?
无赖的篮球运动员
Behold lunkhead basketball man.
盖比瑞拉
So, Gabriella,
我们愿意你参加学术竞赛
we'd love to have you for the scholastic decathlon.
你要吃午餐吗？
Did you wanna grab some lunch?
嗯 如果你去我们在那里等你
Well, we'll be there if you wanna come.
-野猫队！-集中精力比赛！
- Wildcats! - Get your head in the game!
喔
Whoo!
-我们走！ -野猫队！
- Let's go! - Go, Wildcats!
大家一起唱
Everybody sing out
各地的野猫们 居高双手向上跳
Wildcats. Everywhere wave your hands up in the air
这就是我们擅长之事
That's the way we do it let's get to it
来像世人一展长才吧
Time to show the world
野猫们一起唱 你们真的一级棒
Wildcats. Sing along They really got it goin' on
屋子里的野猫们 每个人都齐声唱
Wildcats in the house everybody sing out...
各地的野猫们 居高双手向上跳
Wildcats. Everywhere wave your hands up in the air
特洛伊 特洛伊 特洛伊...
Troy, Troy, Troy...
发现别人对自己的看法
It's funny when you find yourself
真是奇怪的感觉
Looking from the outside
我站在这里 但却渴望过去那里
I'm standing here but all I want is to be over there
为何让自己相信
Why did I let myself believe
奇迹有可能发生?
Miracles could happen?
而现在我必须假装自己毫不在意
'Cause now I have to pretend that I don't really care
我以为你是我的童话
I thought you were my fairy tale
一个真实的梦境
A dream when I'm not sleeping
以为向流星许下愿望
A wish upon a star that's coming true
竟然能够成真
But everybody else could tell
但除了自己以外 大家都看得出
That I confused my feelings with the truth
在你我之间 我错把感觉当成了现实
When there was me and you
我发誓我认得出 你所唱的旋律
I swore I knew the melody that I heard you singing
你的微笑让我相信 我也可以唱和
And when you smiled you made me feel like I could sing along
但是你离去 并说出那样的话语
But then you went and changed the words
使我的心如今空荡一片
Now my heart is empty
只剩下回忆 与已落幕的歌曲
I'm only left with used-to-bes and once upon a song
现在我知道 你不是个童话
Now I know your not a fairy tale
只是睡梦中的梦境
And dreams were meant for sleeping
无法成真的愿望 永远也不会实现
And wishes on a star just don't come true
现在 连我也明白
'Cause now even I can tell
我错把感觉当成了现实
That I confused my feelings with the truth
只因为我喜欢
'Cause I liked the view
我们在一起的感觉
When there was me and you
不敢相信我竟如此盲目
I can't believe that I could be so blind
你不断向上飞 我却往下坠落
It's like you were floating while I was falling
但是我不在意
And I didn't mind
因为我喜欢这样的景色 喔 喔..
Because I liked the view, ooh ooh, ooh, ooh
我以为当我们在一起时
I thought you felt it too
你的感觉也跟我一样
When there was me and you
嗨 你好吗？
Hey, how you doin'?
听着 我想和你谈谈
Listen. I wanna talk to you about ...
是这样的 我明白这好像
And here it is: I know what
是对你朋友的负担
it's like to carry a load with your friends.
我明白
I get it.
你有你的队伍 特洛伊
You've got your boys, Troy.
没关系的 我们就这样吧
It's OK. So we're good.
就怎么样？
Good about what?
我想和你谈谈最后的试镜
I wanna talk about the final callbacks.
我也不想参加试镜了
I don't wanna do the callbacks either.
我们要骗谁？
Who are we trying to kid?
你有你的队伍 我有我
You've got your team and I've got mine.
我会参加学术竞赛
I'll do the scholastic decathlon
你赢你的冠军
and you'll win the championships.
那是我们的归宿
It's where we belong.
-野猫加油 -但我...
- Go, Wildcats. - But I...
我也是
Me neither.
盖比瑞拉？
Gabriella?
野猫加油!
Go Wildcats!
嗨 队长！
Hey, Captain!
-特洛伊怎么了？-别担心
- What's with Troy? - Don't worry about it.
嗨！
Oh, hey!
-特洛伊！嗨 -嗨 特洛伊！
- Troy! Hey. - Hey, Troy!
嗨 嗯...
Hey, um...
我们刚刚开了队会
We just had another team meeting.
哦...
Oh...
好
wonderful.
我们开会讨论
We had a team meeting about how
我们最近表现得不像一只队伍
we haven't been acting like a team.
我指我们 不是你
I mean us, not you.
-关于唱歌的事... -不 不想谈这个
- About the singing thing... - I don't even wanna talk about it.
我们想要你知道
We just want you to know that we're gonna be there.
我们会支持你
that we're gonna be there.
-为你加油 -呃？
- Cheering for you. - Huh?
如果唱歌是你想做的
If singing is what you wanna do,
我们应该支持你
we should boost you up,
不是拖你后腿
not tear you down.
对 无论输赢 我们是队友
Yeah. Win or lose, we're teammates.
这就是我们存在的原因
That's what we're about.
就算你是最烂的歌手也一样
Even if you turn out to be the worst singer in the world.
因为你知道的
Which we don't know,
我们还没听过你唱歌呢!
because we haven't heard you sing.
你们不会听到我唱了
You're not gonna hear me sing, guys.
因为 盖比瑞拉不肯和我讲话了
Because Gabriella won't even talk to me...
而我不知道原因
...and I don't know why.
我们知道
We do.
这是我今天刚刚烤好的
I baked these fresh today.
在听我们解释之前
You'll probably want to try one
或许你会想要吃一个
before we tell you the rest.
盖比瑞拉 我们是混蛋
Gabriella, we were jerks.
不 连混蛋都不如
No, we were worse than jerks
我们是卑鄙的混蛋
because we were mean jerks.
我们以为特洛伊
We thought Troy
和唱歌的事
and the whole singing thing was
会阻止你加入
killing our chances of having you on
我们全能赛代表队
the scholastic decathlon team.
我听到他说的话
I heard what he had to say.
我现在在你的团队 好了
I heard what he had to say. I'm on your team now. Done.
不 不对
No, not done.
而使你忘掉试镜
to make you want to forget about the callbacks.
我们是计划好的
We planned it,
我们很惭愧 对不起
and we're embarrassed and sorry.
没人逼特洛伊说那些话
No one forced Troy to say anything.
你们知道什么? 算了
And you know what? It's OK.
我们知道
We knew that
查德会故意刺激特洛伊摞话
Chad could get Troy to say things
我们现在该为比赛作准备
We should prepare for the decathlon,
该继续前进了
it's time to move on.
不行 不能算了
No, it's not OK.
竞赛不算什么
-The decathlon is whatever,
你怎么看我们
but how you feel about us, and
而且 特洛伊
even more, Troy
很重要
that's what really matters.
我们努力了
We tried.
嗨...我来讲对不起
Hi, uh... Just came to say I'm sorry.
嗨 蒙特兹夫人
- Hi, Miss Montez,
哦 特洛伊！
Oh, Troy!
嗯...
Um...
盖比瑞拉正在做功课
Gabriella is kind of busy with homework,
现在不太方便
so now's not a good time.
我是特洛伊·波顿
I'm Troy Bolton.
我犯了错误
I made a mistake,
蒙特兹夫人
Miss Montez,
我真的想要盖比瑞拉知道这些
and I would really like to let Gabriella know that.
您能转告她我来过吗？
Could you tell her I came by to see her?
我会的...特洛伊
I will... Troy.
-晚安 -晚安 谢谢
- Good night. - Good night. Thank you.
喂？
Hello?
我被我的朋友烦透了
I was sick of my friends riding me,
所以我讲那些使他们停嘴
so I said things to shut them up.
我的意思不是那样的
I didn't mean any of it.
我听起来很相信的
You sounded pretty convincing to me.
听我说 你假期所遇到的我
Listen.The guy you met on vacation is more me
你听到的 都不是真的
What you heard, none of that is true.
是比讲蠢话的我 更真实的我
than the guy who said those stupid things.
这唱歌的事使学校混乱了
The whole singing thing is making the school whack.
就如你说的
You said so yourself.
所有人都因此对你另眼相待了
Everyone's treating you differently because of it.
也许因为我不想仅仅打篮球
Maybe because I don't wanna only be the basketball guy.
他们不能理解
They can't handle it.
不是我的问题 是他们的
That's not my problem. It's theirs.
-你爸爸呢？ -这不关我爸的事
-How about your dad? -And it's not about my dad.
重点是我的感受
This is about how I feel.
我没有放弃球队
And I'm not letting the team down.
他们抛弃我
They let me down.
所以我要唱歌 ？
So I'm gonna sing.
你呢？
What about you?
我不知道 特洛伊
I don't know, Troy.
嗯 你应该说 要
Well. You need to say yes.
因为我给你带来了东西
Because I brought you something.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
转过身来
Turn around.
这是一场全新的旅程
This could be the start of something new
感觉如此美妙
It feels so right
和你在一起
to be here with you
哦
Oh
此刻注视你的双眸
And now lookin' in your eyes
感觉在我心中
I feel in my heart
全新的旅程已然
The start of something...
开始
...new
对唱的剧本
It's a pairs audition.
喔
Whoo.
耶
Yeah!
Zn4 这样一来 就得出2…
Zn4, and by doing that, you end up with two...
和2 明白吗？
...and two. Got it?
明白！
Yes!
怎么了？
What's happening?
来 放5克这个
Come here. Go ahead and put five grams of this in,
会使它成为酸性态
and that causes it to change from an acidic state.
使颜色从粉红变蓝
Causing the color to change from pink to blue.
就像酸碱试纸
Just like those pH strips.
哦 该走了 再见
Oh, gotta go. See you guys later!
哇
Whoa!
你晚了！
You're late!
相信的力量
strength to believe
我们展翅翱翔
We're soarin'
飞行
Flyin'
没有什么浩瀚星辰
There's not a star in heaven
是我们触不到的
that we can't reach
跳 跳 跳上...
Bop bop bop...
只要我们勇于尝试
If we're tryin'
耶 就可挣脱束缚
Yeah, we're breakin' free
哦
Oh
是的 就可挣脱束缚
Oh, we're breakin' free
喔 他们唱得不错
Wow. They sound good.
哦 哦 哦
-Oh  oh oh
你能感到它在心中奔涌
Can you feel it building
像海浪一样不能控制
Like a wave the ocean just can't control
我们得有所行动
We have to do something.
你我心意相连 哦 在我们灵魂...
Connected by a feeling Ooh, in our very ..
好 我们的试镜是周四
OK, our callback is on Thursday
篮球赛
and the basketball game
和学术竞赛是周五
and scholastic decathlon are on Friday.
太遗憾了 它们不在同一天...
Too bad all these events weren't happening on the same day...
同一时间
...at the same time.
哦 若是这样
Well. That wouldn't work out because
特洛伊和盖比瑞拉不能到...
then Troy and Gabriella wouldn't be able to make...
我真以叫你姐姐而自豪
I'm proud to call you my sister.
我知道
I know.
我再也不想听到特洛伊和那蒙特兹了
I don't want to hear any more about Troy and that Montez girl.
所以 如果你作为戏剧社的联合主席
So, if you're telling me as co-presidents of the drama club
改变试镜的时间
that changing the callbacks
对我们的节目很有好处
would be what's best for our theater program,
我会非常同意
I might actually agree with you.
那是同意吗？
Is that a yes?
跳 跳 跳上...巅峰
Bop bop bop, up to the top
抛出你的抱负
And wipe away your inhibitions
踏出 踏出 踏出..舞步 骄傲地赢得胜利
Stomp, stomp, stomp do the romp and strut your stuff
跳 跳 跳吧..舞上巅峰
Bop bop bop, straight to the top...
没问题 太疯狂了
No problem at all. It was crazy, man.
- 还有学术竞赛 -他们为什么这么做？
-And the scholastic decathlon. -Why would they do that?
我觉得是叫达布斯的老鼠在搞鬼
I smell a rat named Darbus.
是两只老鼠在搞鬼
I think two rats,
他们都不叫达布斯
neither named Darbus.
你知道怎么回事吗 小个？
Do you know something about this, small person?
试镜和比赛同时举行？
Callbacks the same time as the game?
达布丝老师 认为这会保护音乐剧
Miss Darbus thinks she's protecting the show,
但瑞安和夏培
but Ryan and Sharpay
只想保护他们自己
are only concerned with protecting themselves.
知道我要怎么对付这两只戏剧狗吗?
Do you know what I'll do to those two show dogs?
没事 我们不会对他们怎样
Nothing. We're not gonna do anything to them.
或许 除了唱歌
Except to sing, maybe.
现在唯一要做的
Now this is only gonna happen
就是我们一起行动
if we all work together.
-谁参加 -你知道算上我
-Now who's in? -You know I'm in.
一个派蛋糕
A pi pie.
-哦 上帝  -哦 上帝
-Oh, my goodness!  -Oh, my gosh!
什么？谢谢！
What? Thank you!
喔 我们也有东西给你们
Oh, we have something for you too.
对 过来 看
Yeah, come here, look.
你看!
Ta-da!
啊...算式
Oh... it's an equation.
哦！
Oh!
太差了！
That's awful!
待在那里 看
Stay right there. Watch.
我们队伍送给你们的
From our team, to yours.
向 前 进 舞 台 戏 剧 社
G-o d-r-a-m-a c-l-u-b.
感叹号
Exclamation point.
嗯 好像野猫队下午会有趣
Well, seems we Wildcats are in for an interesting afternoon.
走
Go.
向 前 ...
G-o-d... dra... Go dra... Go dray...
喔！
- Ugh! - Drame?
你怎么样？
How you feeling?
-紧张  -嗯 我也是
-Nervous. -Yeah, me too.
真希望我能和你一起上场
Wish I could suit up and play with you.
嘿 你有你的角色
Hey, you had your turn.
知道今天 我希望你能带给我什么吗?
You know what I want from you today?
-冠军杯 -不是 那不重要
-The championship. -Well, that'll come or it won't.
我想要的是你能体会乐趣
What I want is for you to have fun.
我知道那些压力
I know all about the pressure.
也许是我给你的太多了
Probably too much of it has come from me.
我真正想要的
What I really want
是看到我的儿子
is to see my son
在他的生命中体会
having the time of his life
我们都喜欢的运动
playing the game we both love.
你给我这个
You give me that,
不管比分如何 我都会笑着睡着的
and I will sleep with a smile on my face no matter what the score.
谢谢 教练 啊...
Thanks, Coach... uh...
爸爸
...Dad.
欢迎来到的10届学术竞赛
Welcome to the tenth annual Scholastic Decathlon.
东部高中野猫队对西部高中骑士队
The East High Wildcats versus the West High Knights.
嗨 这边 这里
Hello! Right here, right here.
-嘛 嘛 嘛 -嘛 嘛 嘛
-Mah, mah, mah! - Mah, mah, mah!
-咦 咦 -啊 啊
-Eeh! Eeh! -Ow! Ow!
停！
Stop!
- 我信任你 -力量
- I trust you. -Energy.
- 来吧 我们来
- Whoo! - Come on, let's do it.
现在是东部高中野猫队！
And now introducing your East High Wildcats!
我们走！
Let's go! Go!
...冠军赛将在东部高中和西部高中！
...for this championship game between East High and West High!
做剧中的主角是挑战 更是责任
Casting the leads of a show is both a challenge and a responsibility.
快乐和负担
A joy and a burden.
我希望你们其他年轻的艺术家一道
I commend you and all other young artists to hold out
为了月亮 太阳和星星
for the moon, the sun and the stars.
我们要一起高飞吗？
Shall we soar together?
夏培和瑞安！
Sharpay and Ryan!
荣幸之至
Mucho gusto!
啊 多么美妙
Ay. Que fabulosa!
哎 哎 哎
Ay! Ay! Ay!
看着我
Me la me
我相信梦想 成为天上的星星
I believe in dreamin', shootin' for the stars
要成为第一名 你必须表现完美
Baby to be number one you've got to raise the bar
来吧 你想跳舞吗？
-Arriba! -Quien es bailar?
拿出我最好的一面 用尽我所有努力
Kickin' and a scratchin', grindin' out my best
拿出一切 爬上成功的阶梯
Anything it takes to climb the ladder of success
每一天都勤奋努力
Work our tails off every day
在比赛中大获全胜 彻底击败对手
Gotta bump the competition blow them all away
真是火热!
-Caliente!-Suave!
非常顺利
Yeah we're gonna
跳 跳 跳上巅峰
Bop, bop, bop bop to the top
跟着节奏摇摆律动
Slip and slide and ride that rhythm
跳跃秀出自己 就算跌倒
Jump and hop hop till we drop
再重新开始
And start again
像只拖把扭来扭去
Zip zap zop pop like a mop
在角落到处游走
Scoot around the corner
尽情享受直到音乐停止
Move it to the groove till the music stops
舞上..巅峰
Do the bop bop, bop to the top
别让它停下来 抵达巅峰..
Don't ever stop bop to the top
给我!给我!闪亮!闪亮!
Gimme, gimme, shimmy, shimmy
...冠军奖杯！
... the coveted championship trophy!
野猫队
Wildcats!
东部高中抢到了开球 开始进攻
East High wins the opening tip. Pushing the ball up the court.
东部高中
East High.
我们成功了！
We did it!
很好！
Great job!
踩踩靴子 转个身子
Shake some booty and turn around
朝他们笑一个
Flash a smile in their direction
露出肌肉
Show some muscle
秀个舞姿
Do the Hustle
好 野猫队 到离开体育馆的时间了
All right, Wildcats, time for an orderly exit from the gym.
西部高中在三分线运球
And West High pushes the ball around the perimeter on the offensive end.
西部高中控球很好
Nice ball movement by West High.
突破...
Driving the lane...
投篮...
shot is up and...
我们有技术故障
We seem to be experiencing some technical difficulties.
我们现在暂停
We've got a timeout on the court here.
我们出了问题 暂停比赛
We have a problem. Stop the game. Stop the game.
裁判表示暂停
Referee has signaled timeout.
大家保持冷静
Everyone please remain calm.
走 走 走 走
Go, go, go, go.
我们会很快解决 与此同时 按安全规定
We'll get this figured out real soon. In the meantime, per safety regulations,
我们需要大家顺序离开体育馆
we need to all make an orderly exit from the gym, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
没错 我们要..
Yeah, we're gonna bop, bop, bop
-舞上..巅峰-抛出你的抱负
-Bop to the top-Wipe away your inhibitions
踏出舞步
Stump, stump, stump do the romp
秀出你的能力
And strut your stuff
跳吧..舞上巅峰
Bop, bop, bop straight to the top
迎接荣耀
Going for the glory
我们会继续跳舞 不会停止 停止
We'll keep stepping up and we just won't stop, stop
直到抵达巅峰
Till we reach the top
舞上巅峰
Bop to the top
嗨 打电话
Oh, hi! Call me.
看到我们为什么热爱剧院了吗？很好！
Do you see why we love the theater, people? Well done!
喔 特洛伊·波顿 盖比瑞拉·蒙特兹
Ah, Troy Bolton, Gabriella Montez.
特洛伊？盖比瑞拉？
Troy?  Gabriella?
他们就来了
They'll be here.
剧院 就像我经常指出的
The theater, as I have often pointed out,
谁也不等 对不起
waits for no one. I'm sorry.
好，我们结束了
Well, we are done here.
祝贺大家 名单会公布
Congratulations to all. The cast list will be posted.
等等 达布丝老师 等等！
Wait! Miss Darbus, wait!
我们准备好了 我们可以唱了
We're ready, we can sing.
我叫过你们两次了
I called your names, twice.
达布丝老师 求你了 求你了
Miss Darbus, please! Please!
规定就是规定！
Rules are rules!
我们愿意再给他们
We'll be happy to do it again
表演一次 达布丝老师
for our fellow students, Miss Darbus.
我不知道这是怎么回事
I don't know what's going on here
但是 太晚了
but in any event,it's far too late
我们没有钢琴师了
and we have not got a pianist.
嗯 正式演出
Well, that's show biz.
我们可以不用钢琴唱
We'll sing without a piano.
哦 不 你们不用
Oh, no, you won't.
钢琴师在这里 达布丝老师
Pianist here, Miss Darbus.
你不想这么做
You really don't wanna do that.
噢 是的 我很乐意
Oh, yes, I really do.
准备演出
Ready on stage.
现在才是正式的演出
Now that's show biz.
我不行 特洛伊
I can't do it, Troy
大家都在看我
not with all these people staring at me.
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey
看着我 专心看着我
look at me, right at me.
就看着我
Right at me.
就好像我们第一次那样 记得吗？
Like the first time we sang together. Remember?
像回到幼儿园一样
Like kindergarten.
我们翱翔 飞行
We're soarin', flyin'
没有什么浩瀚星辰
There's not a star in heaven
是我们触不到的
that we can't reach
只要我们勇于尝试
If we're trying
我们就可挣脱束缚
so we're breaking free
你知道这世界能看见的
You know the world can see us
是我们全然不同的自己
In a way that's different than who we are
空间不断将我们隔开
Creating space between us
直到我们的心分开
till we're separate hearts
但是你的信念会给予我力量
But your faith it gives me strength
相信的力量
strength to believe
我们自由翱翔
We're breakin' free
我们展翅翱翔
We're soarin'
飞行
Flyin'
没有什么浩瀚星辰
There's not a star in heaven
是我们触不到的
that we can't reach
只要我们勇于尝试
If we're tryin'
耶 就可挣脱束缚
Yeah, we're breakin' free
是的 就可挣脱束缚
Oh, we're breakin' free
哦 哦 哦
-Oh  oh oh
像海浪一样不能控制
Like a wave the ocean just can't control
你我心意相连
Connected by a feeling
你能感到它在心中奔涌
Can you feel it building
哦 在我们灵魂深处
Ooh, in our very soul
灵魂深处
Very soul
哦
-Ooh
汹涌澎湃 直至众目共睹
Rising till it lifts us up so everyone can see
我们挣脱束缚
We're breakin' free
我们展翅翱翔
We're soarin'
飞行
Flyin'
没有什么浩瀚星辰
There's not a star in heaven
是我们触不到的
that we can't reach
只要我们勇于尝试
If we're tryin'
是的 就能挣脱束缚
Yeah, we're breaking free
哦 我们挣脱束缚
Oh, we're breakin' free
哦 哦 哦
-Oh  oh oh
奔跑吧
Runnin'
攀爬吧
Climbin'
直到抵达那个地方
To get to that place to
展现真正的自己
be all that we can be
就在此时
Now's the time
我们挣脱束缚
So we're breaking free
We're breaking free Ooh, yeah
超越希望 超越信念
More than hope, more than faith
这是事实 这是命运
This is true, this is fate
你我共行 看它实现
And together we see it comin'
胜过你 胜过我
More than you, more than me
哦 耶耶
Ooh, yeah
不是需要 而是必须
Not a want, but a need
你我共同挣脱束缚
Both of us breakin' free
展翅 高飞
Soarin'  Flyin'
没有什么浩瀚星辰
There's not a star in heaven
是我们触不到的
that we can't reach
只要我们勇于尝试
If we're trying
是的 就能挣脱束缚
Yeah, we're breaking free
挣脱束缚
Breaking free
我们奔跑
We're runnin'
哦 攀爬
Ooh, climbin'
直到抵达那个地方
To get to that place to
展现真正的自己
be all that we can be
就在此时
Now's the time
我们挣脱束缚
We're breakin' free
哦 我们挣脱束缚
Oh, we're breakin' free
哦
Oh
你知道这世界能看见的
You know the world can see us
是我们全新的自己
In a way that's different than who we are
哇~喔~
Whoo!
太棒了！太棒了！
That's amazing!  Amazing, yeah!
西部高中传球
And West High pushin' the ball.
快攻 找空档
Fast break. Looking for an open man.
哦 14号从另一方向断球！
Oh. But it's stolen by number 14 heading back the other way!
东部高中得到球！时间在走！
East High has the ball! Time is running down on the clock!
找空档
Looking for an open man.
假动作 传到外线 在三分线
Fake. Swing to the outside. Ball on the perimeter.
回到内线 好配合
Looks for a man on the inside. Nice screen.
投篮！进了！
Shot's up! And it's good!
东部高中得到冠军！
East High has won the championship!
你们的东部高中野猫队是冠军！
Your East High Wildcats are champions!
祝贺你们 东部高中！
Congratulations. East High!
12码跳投，在最后赢得胜利！
A 12-foot jump shot as time expires for the victory!
特洛伊！特洛伊！特洛伊！
(crowd chants) Troy! Troy! Troy!
-祝贺你 -谢谢
-Congratulations. -Thanks.
过来！ 过来！ 过来！
Coming through! Coming through! Coming through!
-什么队？ -野猫队！
-What team? -Wildcats!
-野猫队！ -来比赛！
- Wildcats! -Get your head in the game!
哦 耶 棒
Oh, yeah, bro!
- 我为你自豪 儿子！ -谢谢 爸爸！
- I'm proud of you, son! - Aw, thanks, Dad!
-好样的 -好样的
-Bravo! -Brava!
- 特洛伊 你真行！ -不 是你！
- (boy) Troy, you're the man! - No, you!
- 祝贺你 野猫队！ -你们队呢？
- Congratulations, Wildcat! - What about your team?
我们也赢了！
We won too!
嘿！我们投票给你这个比赛用球 队长！
Yo! Team voted you the game ball, Captain!
谢谢 太谢谢了
Yeah, thank you. Thanks a lot.
那么...你会和我去庆祝派对，对吗？
So... you're going with me to the after-party, right?
- 约会？-你的幸运日
- Like on a date? - Must be your lucky day.
查德刚刚约我了
Chad just asked me out.
祝贺你
Well, congratulations.
我会继续准备 如果你不能演出
I'll be the understudy in case you can't make a show, so...
比如断了腿
...break a leg.
在剧院里 意思就是祝你好运
In theater that means good luck.
嗨 夏培
Hey, Sharpay.
很遗憾你没主演
I'm sorry you didn't get the lead,
但我认为你很棒
but I think you're really good.
我十分敬佩你
I admire you so much.
为什么不？再见
And, why wouldn't you? Now, bye-bye.
现在 再见
Now, bye-bye.
等等
Wait.
我为你做了些点心
I baked you some cookies. - Ew.
-精彩比赛 -谢谢
- Nice game. - Thanks.
作曲人 这是我们的冠军球
Composer, here's your game ball.
你应当得的 决策人
You deserve it, playmaker.
耶
Yeah!
哦 这才是我说的
Whoo, that's what I'm talkin' about.
我们开始！
Here we go!
一起 在一起 我们一起来
Together, together together, everyone
一起  大家一起来  我们找点乐子
Together, together come on, let's have some fun
一起 无论何时 我们永远支持彼此
Together, we're there for each other every time
一起 大家一起来 大家一起达成目标
Together, together come on, let's do this right
我们在这里 只有同一个声音
We're all here and speaking out with one voice
我们要震撼全世界
We're gonna rock the house, yeah, yeah
耶 耶
Yeah, yeah
我们的梦想没有极限
That all our dreams have no limitations
耶!派对开始了 大家一起制造噪音
The party's on, now everybody make some noise
一起来,每个人都独一无二
Everyone is special in their own way
彼此让对方坚强
-We make each other strong-Each other strong
让对方坚强 我们都不相同 每个人都特殊而美好
Were not the same, we're different in a good way
我们应该团结不分开
Together's where we belong
我们共同面对一切
We're all in this together
明白每个人都是闪亮之星
Once we know that we are we're all stars and we see that
我们共同面对一切
We're all in this together
所以当我们牵着手
And it shows when we stand hand in hand
就能实现梦想
Make our dreams come true
大家一起来
Everybody now
一起  大家一起来  我们找点乐子
Together, together come on, let's have some fun
一起 无论何时 我们永远支持彼此
Together, we're there for each other every time
一起 在一起 我们一起来
Together, together together, everyone
一起 大家一起来 大家一起达成目标
Together, together come on, let's do this right
我们在这里  只有同一个声音
We're all here and speaking out with one voice
我们要震撼全世界
We're gonna rock the house, yeah, yeah
耶!派对开始了 大家一起制造噪音
The party's on, now everybody make some noise
大声尖叫吧
Come on, scream and shout
我们不会出错 因为我们团结在一起
We've arrived because we stuck together
每个人都是冠军
Champions one and all
我们共同面对一切
We're all in this together
明白每个人都是闪亮之星
Once we know that we are we're all stars
我们共同面对一切
And we see that we're all in this together
只要手牵着手
And it shows when we stand hand in hand
就能实现梦想
Make our dreams come
因为我们共同面对
We're all in this together
内心明白 我们一定办得到
We can make it
我们共同面对一切
We're all in his together
一旦看到机会 便紧抓不放
Once we see there's a chance that we have and we take it
伸出双手就能飞翔
When we reach, we can fly know inside
野猫们一起唱
Wildcats sing along
你们真的一级棒
Yeah, you really got it goin' on
屋子里的野猫们
Wildcats in the house
每个人都齐声唱
Everybody say it now
各地的野猫们 举高双手向上跳
Wildcats everywhere wave your hands up in the air
这就是我们擅长之事
That's the way we do it let's get to it
来向世人一展长才吧
Time to show the world
嘿
Hey!
噢
Ho!
一起来吧
Hey! Ho! All right, here we go!
我们共同面对一切
We're all in this together
明白每个人都是闪亮之星
Once we know that we are we're all stars and we see that
我们共同面对一切
We're all in this together
所以当我们牵着手
And it shows when we stand hand in hand
就能实现梦想
Make our dreams come true
因为我们共同面对
We're all in this together
伸出双手就能飞翔 内心明白 我们一定办得到
When we reach, we can fly know inside we can make it
我们共同面对一切
We're all in this together
看到机会便紧抓不放
Once we see there's a chance that we have and we take it
这就是我们的方式
That's the way we do it let's get to it
大家一起来吧!
Come on, everyone!
耶
Yeah!
哦
Whoo.
耶
Yeah!
哦
Whoo.
野猫们一起唱!
Wildcats sing along
你们真的一级棒
They really got it goin' on
屋子里的野猫们
Wildcats in the house
每个人都齐声唱
Everybody sing out
各地的野猫们 举高双手向上跳
Wildcats everywhere, wave your hands up in the air
这就是我们擅长之事
That's the way we do it, let's get to it
来向世人一展长才吧
Time to show the world
野猫们一起唱
Wildcats sing along
你们真的一级棒
Yeah, you really got it goin' on
屋子里的野猫们
Wildcats in the house
每个人都齐声唱
Everybody say it now
各地的野猫们 举高双手向上跳
Wildcats everywhere, wave your hands up in the air
这就是我们擅长之事
That's the way we do it, let's get to it
一展长才..
Time to show..
这些点心太好吃了！
These cookies are genius!
我吃过最好吃的东西！
The best things I've ever tasted!
你还会为我做吗 泽克？
Will you make some more for me, Zeke?
我也许还会为你做奶油布丁
I might even make you a creme brulee.